(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-31T16:54:41.221647",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
皆様、大変長らくお待たせいたしました！
Everyone, thank you so much for the long wait!
かなたん！爆誕！
Kanatan's grand birth!
これから始まってまいります。
It's about to begin.
みんなありがとう、コメントありがとうね。
Thank you everyone, thanks for the comments.
みんなの応援のおかげで大きな爆誕祭を開くことができてとっても嬉しいです。
Thanks to everyone's support, I'm so happy we could hold such a big birthday celebration.
少しでも恩返しができるように今日は一生懸命頑張りたいと思います。
I want to do my absolute best today to give back even a little!
それではみんな、タグ「かなたん爆誕」でいっぱいつぶやいてね。始まりよう、かなたん爆誕！
Well then everyone, tweet a lot with the tag #KanatanBakutan. Let's get started!
ことばにすれば消えちゃう関係なら
If words make our bond vanish,
ことばを消せばいいやって思ってた?
did you think we should just erase words?
恐れてた? だけど あれ? なにか違うかも
Were you scared? But huh? Maybe something's off.
千里の道も一歩から 石のように固いそんな意志で
Every journey begins with a single step, with a resolute will like stone,
塵も積もれば山となでしこ? 「し」抜けで いや 死ぬ気で!
dust piles up to a Yamato nadeshiko? Skip the "shi"? No, with the resolve of death!
ふわふふわり ふわふわる
Fluffily, fluffity,
あなたが名前を呼ぶ それだけで宙へ浮かぶ
when you call my name, just that makes me float in the air.
ふわふわる ふわふわり
Fluffity, fluffily,
あなたが笑っている それだけで笑顔になる
when you smile, just that brings a smile to my face.
神様 ありがとう 運命の悪戯でも
Dear God, thank you, even if it's destiny's prank,
めぐり合えたことが 幸せなの
I'm so happy that we could meet.
でも そんなんじゃだめ
But that's a no-no,
もう そんなんじゃほら
see, that's already
心は進化するよ もーっと もーっと
making our hearts evolve more and more.
そう そんなんじゃやだ
Yup, that's a no-go,
ねえ そんなんじゃまだ
hey, that's a bit too early,
私のこと見ていてね ずーっと ずーっと
don't take your eyes off me, never and ever.
今日は かなたんのお誕生日です！
Today is Kanatan's birthday!
おめでとう！おめでとう！かなたん爆誕しました！
Happy birthday! Congratulations! Kanatan's grand birth!
いえーい！
Yay!
私のなかのあなたほど あなたのなかの私の存在は まだまだ大きくないことも分かってるけれど
I know my presence in you isn't nearly as big as yours is in me, yet...
今この同じ瞬間 共有してる実感
In this exact moment, sharing the feeling that
塵も積もればやまとなでしこ? 略してちりつもやまとなでしこ!
dust piles up to a Yamato nadeshiko? Short for chiritsumo Yamato nadeshiko!
くらりくらり くらりくらる あなたを見上げたら それだけで眩しすぎて
Dizzily, when I look up at you, just that is far too dazzling.
くらりくらる くらりくらり
Dizzying, dizzily,
あなたを思っている それだけで溶けてしまう
thinking of you melts me away just like that.
神様 ありがとう 運命の悪戯でも
Dear God, thank you, even if it's destiny's prank,
めぐり合えたことが 幸せなの
I'm so glad that we could meet.
恋する季節は 欲張りサーキュレーション 恋する気持ちは 気まぐれサーキュレーション
The season of love is a greedy circulation. The feeling of love is a fickle circulation.
恋する瞳は 欲張りサーキュレーション 恋する乙女は 気まぐれサーキュレーション
The eyes of love are a greedy circulation. The maiden of love is a fickle circulation.
恋するものは 欲張りサーキュレーション 奇跡すぐ起きる
For those in love, a greedy circulation, miracles happen right away!
ふわふわり ふわふわる
Fluffily, fluffily...
あなたが名前を呼ぶ それだけで宙へ浮かぶ
When you call my name, just that makes me float in the air.
ふわふわる ふわふわり あなたが笑っている それだけで笑顔になる
Fluffily, fluffily, when you smile, just that makes me smile.
神様 ありがとう
Dear God, thank you.
運命のいたずらでも
Even if it's just destiny's prank,
めぐり逢えたことが 幸せなの
I'm so glad we were able to meet.
でもそんなんじゃだめ もそんなんじゃほら
But that's no good, no, that's not enough, look!
心が進化するよ もっともっと
My heart evolves more and more!
でもそんなんじゃやだ でもそんなんじゃまだ
But I hate that, no, that's still not enough!
私のこと見ててね ずっとずっと
Keep looking at me, always and forever.
甘くて幸せなこと 隠し味何にしよう
What secret ingredient should I use for this sweet happiness?
純粋な乙女心 甘い恋も絡みなくちゃ
A pure maiden's heart must also be tangled with sweet love!
切なさ重ねてミルフィーユ
Layering sorrow like a mille-feuille,
酸味も積み上げタルト
piling up sourness into a tart.
苦味もチョコレートケーキ？
Even bitter chocolate cake?
魔法かけた甘い奇跡
A sweet miracle cast with magic!
甘さを抑えてビターとか
Toning down the sweetness to make it bitter,
ミルクなしのコーヒー とか
or coffee without milk...
甘いだけじゃ大人になれないの？
Can't you become an adult with just sweetness?
そんなの 絶対に 絶対 やだやだやです
Absolutely, completely, I refuse that!
ねぇ あげようか 甘い罠
Hey, shall I give you a sweet trap?
ほら 虜にしてあげる
Look, I'll make you my prisoner.
そんな魔法かけるから
I'll cast such magic,
ちょっとだけ待たせたげるわ
so you'll just have to wait a little bit!
たった一口が足りなくて
Just one bite isn't enough,
赤いイチゴみたい意地張って
acting stubborn like a red strawberry.
甘いところなんて見せないわ
I won't show you my sweet side!
完璧に作るもん 一人でも でも でも
Making it perfectly all by myself, but, but, but...
ねえ 気づいてるんでしょ？
Hey, you've noticed, right?
わかってるんでしょ？
You get it, right?
隠し味の恋心
The secret ingredient of true love.
苦味とか酸味とか
Bitter things, sour things,
そういうのもたまにはいいわ
even those are fine sometimes!
意地張りでワガママな
Because of this stubborn and selfish
そんな「甘い魔法」使い
"sweet magic" user of mine!
たった一口が足りなくて
Just one bite isn't enough,
甘い自己満足だけじゃあって
with only sweet self-satisfaction,
甘いと揃うなんて見せないわ
I won't show you that we match!
完璧に作るもん 一人でも でも でも
Making it perfectly all by myself, but, but, but...
気づいてんでしょ？
You've noticed, right?
わかってんでしょ？
You get it, right?
隠し味の恋心
The secret ingredient of true love.
苦味とか酸味とか
Bitter things, sour things,
そういうのもたまにはいいわ
even those are fine sometimes!
意地張りでワガママな
Because of this stubborn and selfish
そんな「甘い魔法使い」
"sweet magician" user of mine!
たった一口足りなくて
Just one bite isn't enough,
たった一口のケーキだよ
it's just one bite of cake!
どうぞどうぞ召し上がれ
Please, go ahead and eat up!
味見してみてよ ほんとに
Try tasting it, really!
もしかして美味しいの？
Could it actually be delicious?
甘くて幸せなこと
Sweet and happy things,
隠し味何にしよう
what secret ingredient should I use?
純粋な乙女心
A pure maiden's heart,
甘い恋もからめなくちゃ
sweet love must also be intertwined.
切なさを重ねて
Layering the sorrow...
ちっちゃな頃から優等生
An honor student since I was tiny,
気付いたら大人になってた
before I knew it, I became an adult.
ナイフのような思考回路
A thought circuit like a knife,
持ち合わせる訳もなく
with no way to match it.
でも遊び足りない 何か足りない
Still not enough play, something's missing.
困っちゃうこれは誰かのせい
It's troubling, is this someone's fault?
あてもなくただ混乱するエイデイ
Aimlessly just getting confused every day.
最新の流行は当然の把握
Naturally grasping the latest trends,
経済の動向も通勤時チェック
checking economic trends on my commute.
清純な精神で入社ワーク
Entering the workforce with a pure spirit,
社会人じゃ当然のルールです
it's only natural rules as a member of society.
あなたが思うより健康です
I'm healthier than you think.
一切合切凡庸なあなたじゃ分からないかもね
You might not understand my mediocrity.
謳歌よく似合う
It suits the song so well,
その可もなく不可もないメロディー
that mediocre melody.
頭の出来が違うので問題はナシ
No problem since brains are built differently.
つくづく模範人間
Through and through a model human,
殴ったりするのはノーセンキュー
no thank you to hitting others.
だったら言葉の銃口をその頭に突き付けて撃てば
Then if you press the muzzle of words to that head and shoot,
マジヤバない?止まれやしない
isn't that crazy? It won't stop.
不平不満垂れて成れの果て
Complaining and reaching the end,
サディスティックに変貌する精神
a mind transforming into something sadistic.
酒が空いたグラスあればすぐに注ぎなさい
Pour drinks when glasses are empty.
皆がつまみ易いように串外しなさい
Take off the skewer so everyone can eat easily.
会計や注文は先陣を切る
Check and order before anyone does.
不文律最低限のマナーです
These are the minimum rules of social manners.
くせっ口塞げや限界です
Close your stinking mouth, I can't stand it.
絶対絶対現代の代弁者は私らがいるもう見飽きたわ
I am the modern spokesperson, I'm fed up with it.
二番煎じ換えのパロディ
Those rehash parodies of yours.
うっせぇわ
Usseewa!
あなたが思うより健康です
I'm healthier than you think.
一切合切凡庸なあなたじゃ分からないかもね
You might not understand my mediocrity.
謳歌つめない
You can't sing it well.
何回聴かせんだそのメモリー
How many times do I have to hear that memory?
うっせぇわ
Usseewa!
私も大概だけどどうだっていいぜ問題はナシ
I know I'm no big deal either, but no problem at all.
うっせぇわ
Usseewa!
あなたが思うより健康です
I'm healthier than you think.
一切合切凡庸なあなたじゃ分からないかもね
You might not understand my mediocrity.
謳歌尽きない
My singing won't end.
その限りなく深くないメロディー
That infinitely shallow melody.
うっせぇわ
Usseewa!
頭の出来が違うので問題はナシ
No problem since brains are built differently.
つくづく模範人間
Through and through a model human,
殴ったりするのはノーセンキュー
no thank you to hitting others.
だったら言葉の銃口をその頭に突き付けて撃てばマジヤバない?
Then if you press the muzzle of words to that head and shoot, isn't that crazy?
いつもどおりの通り独り
As usual, alone on the street.
こんな日々もはや懲り懲り
I'm sick and tired of days like this.
いつだって僕らはこんな風に
We're always like this,
ぼんくらな夜に飽き飽き
tired of these dull nights.
また踊り出す明日に出会うためにさようなら
Goodbye, so we can meet tomorrow and dance again.
曖昧も分かんない
I don't even know what's ambiguous,
四半世紀の結果できた 青い顔のスーパーさが
the pale-faced superstar born from a quarter-century result
お腹すかすでは待っている
is waiting with an empty stomach.
曖昧がどうせだったらさ、そぼえなんていいだろう
If it's going to be ambiguous anyway, isn't being ignored fine?
もう一回、もう一回ってさ、僕らの交差
"One more time, one more time," our intersections...
曖昧がずっと前から聞こえてた
Ambiguity has been audible from long ago,
いつかロケットに隠した声が
the voice I once hid inside a rocket.
ああ あの心のしたなんか
Ah, beneath that heart or something,
最善の空は悪天候、ほら窓から覗いて待ってるの、片隅にのよ
the best sky is bad weather, peeking from the window in the corner.
夜も格闘もしの人よ、中指立ててもしょうがないの
Oh person struggling through the night, flipping the middle finger won't help.
今立ち上がるための勉強、ほがらかさないでちょうだい
Studying to stand up now, please don't cheer up.
泥風に見るよほまれの、それを見習って笑わの
Looking like mud, the honor, I'll emulate that and laugh.
でかい知識がかき込んで、もうすり減って残る酸っぱいぶどう
Huge knowledge writing in, the sour grapes left worn out.
膝抱えてもなにもね、ほらなんか今えがみで前髪えね
Hugging your knees does nothing, hey, drawing bangs right now...
笑っちまうね、ぱっとわっかってこう、あっと消えて入るこんなにね
I end up laughing, suddenly understanding, disappearing instantly.
愛されたいならそうよね、待ってるだけじゃ伝わらないね
If you want to be loved, just waiting won't get across.
永遠の宿もそっと抜いて、孤独は遠くの方へ
Gently slipping out of the eternal inn, loneliness heads far away.
ああ分かっていたってさ、転がる俺は巻きぬ
Ah, even if I knew, I, rolling, get wrapped up.
ただどこでもいいから遠くへ行きたいんだ
I just want to go far away anywhere.
それだけなんだ、耳を澄ませとくれ今、響き出した音を逃がすな、呼吸を整えて
Lend me your ear, don't let the sound escape, regulate your breathing.
いつかは出会えるはずの、ほがでのい乗したいモライト
The light we should eventually meet...
きっと掴んで放した
Surely grabbed and let go.
曖昧が何もないならどうなったっていいだろう
If there's nothing ambiguous, whatever happens is fine, right?
楽しかったってみんなにちゃっとすぐにハイントサヨナラ
"It was fun," chatting to everyone right away, "hain," goodbye.
曖昧がきっといつかだって願うまま進め、10回目のその窓を越えて愛されたいならそう言おうぜ
Proceed as you wish, crossing the 10th window, if you want to be loved, let's say so.
待ってるだけじゃ伝わらないね、永遠の宿もそっと抜けて
Just waiting won't get across, gently slipping out of the eternal inn.
孤独は遠くの方へ、ああ分かっていたってさ
Loneliness heads far away, ah, even if I knew.
転がる俺は巻きぬ、ただどこでもいいから遠くの方へ
I, rolling, get wrapped up, just anywhere far away...
ここいらでひとつ揃えてみようぜ、歪みだけでも転がってこうぜ
Let's gather one here, let's roll even with distortions.
聞こえてるなら声に出してこうぜ
If you can hear it, let's voice it out.
曖昧がどうせだったらさ、そぼえなんていいだろう
If it's going to be ambiguous anyway, isn't being ignored fine?
もう一回、もう一回ってさ、僕らの交差
"One more time, one more time," our intersections...
曖昧がずっと前から聞こえてた
Ambiguity has been audible from long ago,
いつかロケットに隠した声が
the voice I once hid inside a rocket.
ここいらでひとつ育ててみようぜ、いざ出かけるまで転がってこうぜ
Let's grow one here, let's roll until we head out.
聞こえてるなら声に出してこうぜ、イエイ、イエイ、イエイ
If you can hear it, let's voice it out, yeah, yeah, yeah!
はーい！いえーい！ねねちゃんおめでとう！
Yay! Yeah! Congratulations, Nene-chan!
ということでね、えー、ねねちゃんがね、来て下さいました！
And so, Nene-chan came to join us!
ねねちゃんがね、来て下さいました！
Nene-chan came to join us!
ちょっと、えー！
Wait, um!
できてほやほやの
Brand new, freshly made...
そう、ねねちゃんにはね、本当にね
Yes, to Nene-chan, really...
あの、ぜひね一緒に歌いたいっていう話をしておりまして
We talked about definitely wanting to sing together...
その、3Dのお披露目が、まああると、そのときにね、3月の終わりぐらいだったっけ、オファーしたの。
Around the end of March, I offered it for her 3D reveal.
そしたら受けてくれたんで、もうそれは絶対に！
And she accepted it, so that was definitely!
出てほしいねってね、話したよね。そう、嬉しかった！
We talked about wanting her to appear. Yes, I was so happy!
これからはいっぱいこうやって、涙出たいとか、一緒にね3Dで遊んだりとか
From now on, let's play in 3D together a lot,
しようね、ずっと待っててよ！本当にやってやった！
let's do that! We really made it happen!
ねねちゃん、の、凄さ！え？ ちょっと待いちゃんね
Nene-chan's greatness! Wait, Mai-chan...
息一つ上がってないやん、僕！
I'm not out of breath at all!
めちゃくちゃ疲れてるな、ちょっと。やばい、ぜんぜんちょっとね
I'm super tired. Oh no, not at all...
ねねちゃん余裕さん、ちょっと。ね、いいね、いいね。ちょっとねねちゃんの本気度だからね
Nene-chan is so relaxed. This is Nene-chan's serious mode,
もっとこの、ね、歌いたいよね。ふたりで一緒に歌うとこ見たいんだよね、みんな。
so everyone wants to see us singing together more.
楽しかったよね、本当。嬉しいの、本当に。
It was fun, really. I'm so happy, truly.
本当、今日おめでとうございます！ありがとう！ありがとう、ねねちゃん！
Truly, congratulations today! Thank you, Nene-chan!
お誕生日がある主役だからね、本日の。本日の主役です！
You're today's protagonist because it's your birthday!
そう、嬉しいね。また、これからもね、いっぱいうたったりとか、コラボもね。
Yes, I'm so happy. Let's sing a lot and collaborate more from now on.
やろう！やろうぜ！
Let's do it! Let's do it!
いっぱいやろう！いっぱいやろうぜ！スーパーねねち！
Let's do lots! Let's do lots, Super Nenechi!
イェーイ！
Yay!
という感じで、はい。
Something like that, yep.
ねね、歌って、歌ったのはルーザーでございますが、
Nene, singing... we sang "Loser," but—
え、かっこいい曲だったけど今度はね、ちょっと電波の曲とかも、ぼくはねねちゃんと歌ってみたいので、
that was a cool song, but this time, I want to try singing a more quirky song with Nene-chan, so—
え、やろうやろう！
Oh, let's do it!
ぜひ！
Absolutely!
歌いましょうね。おねがいします。やろうやろう！いいね。
Let's sing together. Please. Let's do it! Sounds good.
ってな感じで、はい、それではですね、うん。
With that said, alright, now then...
お次の曲の準備をいたしましょうか。はい。
Shall we prepare for the next song? Yep.
それでは、
Now then...
世界五分前仮説
[Song: Five-Minute World Hypothesis]
相対性生存の 抽象的レゾリューション
Abstract resolution of relative survival,
苛々されてく 繰り言 狂響曲
frustrating, repetitive complaints in a symphony of madness.
予測不能 生存現実 科学的サイクロイド
Unpredictable survival reality, scientific cycloid,
苛々されてく 飲み込む 主従無情
swallowing frustration, master-servant heartlessness.
ライアの少年は 信者を買いかぶり
The liar boy overestimates believers,
小さく笑う 世界に意味はないと
smiling faintly, thinking the world has no meaning.
ディスプレー上の数理の
Mathematical logic on the display,
曖昧化した 愛と青の境界 存在の
ambiguous boundaries of love and blue, existence—
たとえ世界がみなし、
even if the world is deemed—
ここまでも咲き揃い 否定している
blooming all the way here, and being denied.
どうしたら？
What should we do?
生存圏
Survival sphere,
再生圏
regeneration sphere.
あぁ 僕ら切ない 世界を奏でていく
Ah, we weave a sorrowful world as we play on.
次はアジサイが咲いてくれます！
Next, the hydrangeas will bloom!
やったー！
Yay!
みなさんお誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday to everyone!
予言者も誰もがな、その証明などできないのさ
No prophet or anyone else can ever prove it.
あぁ 君は何を言い叫んだんだろ
Ah, what was it that you cried out?
ロボットはレプリカを、信者は真実を、少年は世界を
The robot seeks replicas, the believer truth, the boy the world.
みんなまだまだ盛り上がれるかー！盛り上がっていくぞー！
Can everyone still get hyped?! Let's go!
あぁ たとえば世界がみな、五分前の世界すら拒絶している
Ah, even if the world rejects even the world of five minutes ago—
どうしたら？ 生存圏 再生圏
What should we do? Survival sphere, regeneration sphere.
予言者も誰もがな、その証明などできないのさ
No prophet or anyone else can ever prove it.
どうしてなの、音の鳴る鍋を
Why is it that a pot making sound—
あぁ 買い込んで、優しい世界を育てていく
Ah, we stock up and nurture a gentle world.
生存 誰もがみな、その答えすらできないのさ
Survival, nobody can even give that answer—
あぁ 僕ら切ない、形違う二人を
Ah, we two sorrowful ones with different shapes...
あの日見渡した渚を 今も思い出すんだ
I still find myself remembering the shore we looked over that day,
砂の上に刻んだ言葉 君の後ろ姿
And the words carved into the sand, and your back as you walked away.
寄り添う波が足元を よぎり何かをさらう
The lapping waves wash over my feet, washing something away.
夕凪の中 日暮れだけが通り過ぎていく
In the twilight, only the nightfall passes us by.
パッと光って咲いた 花火を見ていた
We watched the fireworks flash and bloom.
きっとまだ終わらない夏が
Surely, summer is not over yet.
曖昧な心を透過して繋いだ
Connected through our uncertain hearts,
この夜が続いて欲しかった
I wanted this night to go on forever.
あと何回君と同じ 花火を見られるかなって
How many more times can I see these fireworks with you?
笑う顔に何ができるだろうか
I wonder what I can do with a smiling face.
傷付くこと喜ぶこと 繰り返す波と情動焦燥
Getting hurt, feeling happy, repeating waves and impatience,
最終列車の音
The sound of the last train.
何度でも言葉にして 君を呼ぶよ
I'll put it into words and call out to you again and again.
波間を選び もう一度
Choosing the waves, once more.
もう二度と悲しまずに済むように
So we can get through it without feeling sad ever again.
ハッと息をのば 消えちまいそうな光が
If I hold my breath, a light that might fade away...
きっとまだ胸に住んでいた
Was surely still living in my heart.
手を伸ばせば触れた あったかい未来は
Reaching out my hand, the warm future I touched...
ひそかに二人を見ていた
Secretly watched over the two of us.
パッと花火が 夜に咲いた
Fireworks bloomed in the night,
夜に咲いて静かに消えた
Bloomed in the night and quietly faded away.
離さないで もう少しだけ
Don't leave me, just a little longer,
もう少しだけ このままで
Just a little longer, just like this.
あの日見渡した渚を 今も思い出すんだ
I still find myself remembering the shore we looked over that day,
砂の上に刻んだ言葉 君の後ろ姿
And the words carved into the sand, and your back as you walked away.
パッと光って咲いた 花火を見ていた
We watched the fireworks flash and bloom.
きっとまだ終わらない夏が
Surely, summer is not over yet.
曖昧な心を透過して繋いだ
Connected through our uncertain hearts,
この夜が続いて欲しかった
I wanted this night to go on forever.
ラララ
La-la-la...
あの日見渡した渚を 今も思い出すんだ
I still find myself remembering the shore we looked over that day,
砂の上に刻んだ言葉 君の後ろ姿
And the words carved into the sand, and your back as you walked away.
パッと光って咲いた 花火を見ていた
We watched the fireworks flash and bloom.
きっとまだ終わらない夏が
Surely, summer is not over yet.
曖昧な心を透過して繋いだ
Connected through our uncertain hearts,
この夜が続いて欲しかった
I wanted this night to go on forever.
あと何回君と同じ 花火を見られるかなって
How many more times can I see these fireworks with you?
笑う顔に何ができるだろうか
I wonder what I can do with a smiling face.
あの日見わたした渚を
I can still remember the shore we saw that day...
今も思い出すんだ
I still remember it now.
砂の上に刻んだ言葉 君の後ろ姿
The words we carved into the sand... the sight of you as you turned away.
寄り添う波が足元をよぎり
The approaching waves wash over my feet,
何かをさらう
sweeping something away.
夕凪の中 日暮れだけが通り過ぎていく
Only the fading twilight passes by in the dusk.
パッと光って咲いた花火を見ていた
I was watching fireworks bloom in a flash.
きっとまだ終わらない夏が
Surely a summer that isn't over yet
曖昧な心を解いて繋いだ
has unlocked my uncertain heart and tied it together.
この夜が続いて欲しかった
I wanted this night to go on forever.
あと何回君と同じ花火を見られるかなって
I wonder how many times I'll see the same fireworks as you?
笑う顔に何が出来るだろうか
What can I do for that smiling face?
I'm a dreamer ひそむパワー
I'm a dreamer, hidden power.
私の世界 夢と恋と不安でできている
My world is made of dreams, love, and worries.
でも想像もしないもの 隠れているはず
Even so, things I can't imagine must be hidden away.
空に向かう木々のようにあなたを まっすぐ見つめている
Like trees facing the sky, I'm gazing straight at you.
見つけたいな 叶えたいな
I want to find it, I want to make it come true.
信じるそれだけで 越えられないものはない
Just believing is enough to overcome anything.
歌うように 奇跡のように
Like a song, like a miracle,
思いがすべてを変えていくよ
feelings change everything.
きっと きっと 驚くくらい
Surely, surely, almost surprisingly!
I'm a dreamer ひそむパワー
I'm a dreamer, hidden power.
まだ見ぬ世界 そこで何が待っていても
No matter what awaits in a world yet unseen,
もしも理想とちがっても 恐れはしない
even if it differs from my ideals, I won't be afraid.
鳥たちは風にのり旅をしてゆく 今日から明日へと
Birds ride on the wind on a journey from today to tomorrow.
伝えたいな 叫びたいな
I want to tell you, I want to shout it out!
この世に一つだけの存在である私
I am the only existence in this world.
祈るように 星のように
Like a prayer, like a star,
小さな光だけいい いつかは もっと もっと つよくなりたい
even with a small light, I want to become stronger and stronger someday.
限界のない可能性がここにある この手に
Limitless possibilities are right here in my grasp.
(It's gonna be your world)
見つけたいな 叶えたいな
I want to find it, I want to make it come true.
信じるそれだけで 越えられないものはない
Just believing is enough to overcome anything.
歌うように 奇跡のように
Like a song, like a miracle,
思いがすべてを変えていくよ
feelings change everything.
きっと きっと 驚くくらい
Surely, surely, almost surprisingly!
鳥たちは風にのり 旅をしてゆく 今日から明日へと
No matter what happens, we'll keep making our journey starting today.
伝えたいな 叫びたいな
I want to tell you, I want to shout it out!
この世に一つだけの存在である私
I am the only existence in this world.
祈るように 星のように
Like a prayer, like a star,
小さな光だけれど いつかは もっと もっと つよくなりたい
even with a small light, I want to become stronger and stronger someday.
限界のない可能性がここにある この手に
Limitless possibilities are right here in my grasp.
見つけたいな 叶えたいな
I want to find it, I want to make it come true.
信じるそれだけで 越えられないものはない
Just believing is enough to overcome anything.
歌うように 奇跡のように
Like a song, like a miracle,
思いがすべてを変えていくよ
feelings change everything.
きっと きっと 驚くくらい
Surely, surely, almost surprisingly!
見つけたいな 叶えたいな
I want to find it, I want to make it come true.
信じるそれだけで 越えられないものはない
Just believing is enough to overcome anything.
歌うように 奇跡のように
Like a song, like a miracle,
思いがすべてを変えていくよ
feelings change everything.
きっと きっと 驚くくらい
Surely, surely, almost surprisingly!
I'm a dreamer 潜むパワー 私の世界
I'm a dreamer, hidden power, my world
夢と恋と不安でできてる
Is made of dreams, love, and worries
でも予想もしないもの 隠れてるはず
But things I never expected must be hiding away
はーい、てことでみんな聞こえてるかな？
Hi! So, can everyone hear me?
ここまで、ちょっと待って、ここまで届けさせていただきましたカナタマートね。
Up to here—hold on. Kanata Mart delivered this up to here, right?
まろめんのみんなに本当に本当にいっぱい協力していただいて、今日ね迎えることができました。
Maromen, thank you all so, so much for your cooperation, and we were able to welcome today.
じゃあもう本当にみんなありがとう。僕らはね、あのみんなの力をこんなに借りていいのかなと
So really, everyone, thank you. Can we borrow everyone's power this much?
えーすごくあのリハの時とかもね思っていたんですが、
Um, I was thinking about it a lot during rehearsals and stuff,
ホロライブというね、えーところに僕もとってもあの本当にいろんなことをね、いろんなものをいただいているので
Since I receive so many things from Hololive as well,
え、ちょっとでもね、ホロライブ好きなみんなが楽しいなって思えるようなそんなライブにできたら嬉しいなと思う！
Um, I'd be happy if we could make a live show where everyone who loves Hololive can have fun!
ってな感じで、このあたりへ何かつまりさん、おしらせがいくつもございます。まずはこちら！
With that said, I have several announcements here. First is this!
えー、天音かなた誕生日記念のね、グッズが出ます。ボイスもね、一緒にでます。
Um, Amane Kanata's birthday merchandise is coming out! Voice packs will be released too.
今回はね、おしおママに描き下ろし、今回も描き下ろししてもらいました。見て！これ水族館で君とさ、
This time, Oshio-mama drew new art for us. Look! It's me and you on a date at an aquarium,
ちょっとデートをしているときのおめかしの僕なんだけど、どうかな？
all dressed up. What do you think?
ええとね、アクリルブロック、マグカップ、そして学生証！ね、みんなさ、マグカップと学生証欲しいってさ、
an acrylic block, a mug, and a student ID card! Hey, everyone, you kept saying you wanted a mug and student ID card,
ね、言ってたでしょ？僕とさ、喋ってたじゃん、おぼえてる？それをね、今回はご用意させていただきました！そしてね、あの全部セット購入者特典というものには
right? We talked about it, remember? Well, this time we got them ready for you! And for those who purchase the complete set,
直筆でメッセージもさせていただきます！えーもうね、概要欄にね、あのグッズ、あ、ほら、こんな感じ、あ、ほら、こちら！
I'll handwrite a message on it too! Um, the merchandise links are in the description—ah, look, like this, ah, look, here!
アクリルブロックこんなんなの、見て見て見て見て、かわいいでしょ？これね、結構大きめのサイズでございます。あ、あ、トレンドも出てた？
Look at this acrylic block, look, look, isn't it cute? This is a pretty large size. Oh, did it also trend?
タグの、タグのトレンドも入って、おった？おった！みんな、みんな本当にありがとう！そして学生証、出るかな？学生証、マグカップ、あ、マグカップ、あ、学生証出た！
Did the hashtag trend too? It did! Everyone, thank you so much! And the student ID card—let's see. Student ID, mug, ah, mug—ah, student ID is here!
見て、これ！ねえ！いいでしょ、生徒手帳風デザインでこれ！
Look at this! Hey! Isn't it nice? It's designed like a student handbook!
これぜひ手に入れてほしい！そしてね、ちょっとここにさ、あ上のほうに書いてあるけど、学生証にはね、シリアルナンバーが入るので、
I definitely want you to get this! And, as it says up top, the student ID card will have a serial number on it,
世界で1つだけになっておりまーす！
so it will be the only one in the entire world!
みんな世界で1枚の学生証をね、ゲットしてほしいなと、思います。
I hope everyone can get their own one-of-a-kind student ID card.
マグカップも出るかな。どどーん、こんな感じでね。ハッピーバースデーありがとう、本当に！ってな感じで、えーっと、もうね概要欄にグッズの販売ページ乗っていると思いますが、
The mug will also be available. Ta-da, like this. Happy birthday, thank you so much! And so, um, the merchandise sales page should already be in the description,
えーっと、10時かな？このあとすぐ22時に、え、販売開始かな？購入ができると思います。アクセスできると思いますので、みんなチェックしてみてね！
um, at 10:00? Right after this at 22:00, sales will start, right? You should be able to purchase it and access it, so everyone check it out!
そしてそして！そしてそして、あ、こちら！あ、全部セット、あ、これみんな見て、こっそりね、僕のあのサインちょっと、あのこっそりさ、ちょっと変わったの。
And then! And then, ah, here! Ah, the complete set, ah, everyone look at this, secretly, my signature changed a little bit, secretly,
あのね、この猫たんと、あの羽とかの位置がね、ちょっと逆になったりしたんです。
you know, the position of this cat and the wings and stuff got a bit reversed.
ね、見て、かわいいでしょ？ぜひぜひ手に入れてね！
See, isn't it cute? Please make sure to get your hands on it!
ありがとう。そして、そして、そして、そして、どどん！
Thank you. And then, and then, and then, ta-da!
どどどどん！じゃあ！明日は同じ4期生のね、同期桐生ココの新しいお披露目です！
Ta-da-da-da! Now! Tomorrow is the new outfit reveal for my fellow 4th gen member, Kiryu Coco!
明日の、えっと、10時だったかな？22時ですね！に、ここが新衣装のお披露目をするので、みんなぜひ見てください！
Tomorrow at, um, was it 10:00? 22:00, right? Coco will be revealing her new outfit, so everyone please watch!
で、このさ、ちょっとシルエットだとね、なんか、なんだろう、ツインテールみたいな感じだけど、服着てんのかって感じもね、正直してるんですが、
And, in this silhouette, it looks kinda like twin tails, though honestly it feels like wondering if she's even wearing clothes,
ま、正直してるんですが、どんな感じになるかぜひ明日見てね！そしてそのあとね、23時からは明日夜4期生のモンハンコラボがあります！
but see what it turns out like tomorrow! And then after that, starting at 23:00 tomorrow night, there's a 4th gen Monster Hunter collab!
ぼくはちょっと実況ということでね、4人のプレイをもうね、見たいなと終わりますので、そちらもチェックよろしく！
Since I'll be doing commentary, I really want to watch the four of them play, so please check that out too!
そしてそして！じゃじゃじゃーん！
And then! Ta-da!
じゃーん！どどーんときた！え、ドルオタ天使！もうね、明日、明日の12時半、お昼で、お昼の12時半に開始いたします！
Ta-da! Ta-da! Doruota Tenshi! Um, starting tomorrow at 12:30, at noon, 12:30 PM!
毎週火・水・金のお昼から、30分、20分くらいの枠でホロライブの紹介番組をやりたいなと思っております！みんなね、ぜひぜひ遊びに来てください！
Every Tuesday, Wednesday, and Friday at noon, for about 30 or 20 minutes, I want to do a Hololive introduction show! Everyone, please come hang out!
ホロライブのことをね、まだわかんないな、知らないなっていう方にもぜひぜひ知っていただきたいなというね、そんな感じで企画をやってまいります！
For those who still don't know much about Hololive, I really want you to get to know it, so we'll be doing this kind of project!
イエーイ！じゃじゃーん、ありがとう！そして、えー、もう一つ、じゃじゃじゃじゃーん、こちら！
Yay! Ta-da, thank you! And, um, one more thing—ta-da, here!
今回が始まりますのでぜひ見てくださいよろしく
This broadcast is starting, so please check it out. Thank you!
そして最後に
And finally,
ドドン！すごいお知らせがあります！
Tada! There's an amazing announcement!
ドドドドドン！
Bam bam bam bam!
やっと発表できた！みんな！
It's finally been announced, everyone!
とうとうオリジナル曲を作っていただけることになりました！
We're finally going to have an original song made for us!
そしてみんなが知ってる、あの田淵さん、あのマジでマジだから、本当だからね！
And you all know him... Tabuchi-san! Seriously, this is for real!
もしですね、あのオリジナル曲もね、だいぶもう進んでおりますので、ぜひ続報をお待ちください！
The original song is already well underway, so please look forward to further updates!
すごいぞ！で、みんなちょっとマジでさ、あの、もしかしたらこの配信のね、この部分をさ、田淵さんがご覧になる可能性があるわけ。
It's huge! And guys, seriously... Tabuchi-san might actually be watching this exact part of the stream.
だからちょっと皆さん、「やべっ！田淵さんちょっとやばい」っていうのをさ、ちょっと、まあ、言わなくても言ってるね？言ってる、言ってる、言ってる！もうこれ見られるか、みんな見られるからな、田淵さんに。
So everyone like, "Oh crap, Tabuchi-san is crazy"—well, even if you don't say it, you are! Tabuchi-san's gonna see this!
よろしくね！
Treat us well!
てな感じで、
So with that said,
えーと、それではね、お知らせはこの様な感じでドドンドンと行きましたが、
um, well, the announcements went with a bang like this,
あとね、シークレットゲストはまだね、登場していないし、ってな感じで、
and also, the secret guest hasn't even appeared yet, so,
え、一曲をね、ソロで歌わせて頂きたいと思います。え、プレミア公開はこの後する「ヒバナ」。
um, I'd like to sing a song solo. Um, "Hibana" premiering right after this.
こんがらがってくして乗りこなせ心の発火点
Tangled up, ride it out, the ignition point of the heart
もうそうばかりデプレッションして高速スパパと擦る答えはどこだろ
Just depressing with delusions, high-speed supapa, where is the answer?
弱音はミュートしてくだらないことで中傷して冗談ばかりでハァハァハァ
Mute complaints, slander with nonsense, just joking, ha ha ha
壊れない壁ごくすぐ迫るでしょう
An unbreakable wall will approach very soon, right?
そんなわけないや
No way,
分かってくれるでしょ
you'll understand, right?
その頭を撃ち抜いて
Shoot through that head
終わんない愛を歌いたくはないのもっとちゃんと罰してよ
I don't want to sing unending love, punish me properly more
狙い撃んで演じてほしいのもっとちゃんと答えてよ
Aim and act out, answer me properly more
未完成だって何度でも呼んで
Even if it's incomplete, call me as many times as you want
脳から掠った愛の中で
Within the love scraped from the brain
とんとんとそれで終わりこってり笑えない時に困っちゃって
Tap tap, and that's the end, rich and unable to laugh, getting troubled
完全主義を装きにこうもくする恋に不意打ち舞い戻りに
Pretending perfection, sudden surprise in love coming back
飲みこんじゃえ BTS気付かないふりでふざけんな生殺しのフェイクって
Swallow it, BTS, pretending not to notice, kidding me, a life-in-death fake
知らないふりでアリスゲイム
Playing Alice playing dumb
いいからギブアップだそうエンドファイアウェイ
Just give up, that's end fire away
愛やどっちも選んで
Choose either love
愛やどっちも壊して
Destroy either love
心の目を引き抜いて
Pull out the eyes of the heart
深い愛愛を愛したくないのもっとちゃんと隠してよ
I don't want to love deep love, hide it properly more
狙い撃ちクライの傷痛いのもっとちゃんと飛ばしてよ
The targeted cry wound hurts, blow it away properly more
未完成だってなんだって何度でも呼んで
Even if it's incomplete, call me as many times as you want
脳から掠った愛の中で
Within the love scraped from the brain
未完成だってなんだって何度でも呼んで
Even if it's incomplete, call me as many times as you want
脳から掠った愛の中で
Within the love scraped from the brain
愛やそんなわけないや愛や分かってくれるでしょ
No way, you'll understand, right?
その頭を撃ち抜いて
Shoot through that head
終わんない愛を歌いたくはないのもっとちゃんと罰してよ
I don't want to sing unending love, punish me properly more
狙い撃んで演じてほしいのもっとちゃんと答えてよ
Aim and act out, answer me properly more
未完成だってなんだって何度でも呼んで
Even if it's incomplete, call me as many times as you want
脳から掠った愛の中で
Within the love scraped from the brain
nanana NOを空振った愛の中で
Na-na-na, inside a love that swung and missed a NO
散々愛し尽くしたいの
I want to love you to my heart's content
もっとちゃんと焦がしてよ
Make me burn even more properly
泣けないくらいにきっと楽しいの
It's bound to be so fun I won't even be able to cry
もっとちゃんと探してよ
Search for me even more properly
nanana
未完成なんてなものでもいいんだ
Even if it's something like "incomplete," that's fine
nanana NOを空振った愛の中で
Na-na-na, inside a love that swung and missed a NO
散々愛し尽くしたいの
I want to love you to my heart's content
未完成なんてなものでもいいんだ
Even if it's something like "incomplete," that's fine
nanana NOを空振った愛の中で
Na-na-na, inside a love that swung and missed a NO